export const data = [
    {
      question: "Name the atmospheric layer closest to the ground",
      option1: "Troposphere",
      option2: "Mesosphere",
      option3: "Thermosphere",
      option4: "Stratosphere",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The most abundant gas on the earth’s atmosphere is",
      option1: "Oxygen",
      option2: "Carbon",
      option3: "Nitrogen",
      option4: "Hydrogen",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "An altitude of 100 kilometres (62 mi; 330,000 ft) above the Earth’s sea level marks the beginning of space where human travellers are considered astronauts. What is it called?",
      option1: "Appleton–Barnett layer",
      option2: "Karman line",
      option3: "Heaviside layer",
      option4: "Van Allen belts",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "What atmospheric layer has most of the clouds?",
      option1: "Mesosphere",
      option2: "Thermosphere",
      option3: "Exosphere",
      option4: "Troposphere",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "The study of weather is called?",
      option1: "Meteorology",
      option2: "Climatology",
      option3: "Aeronomy",
      option4: "Aerology",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which one of the following is NOT a primary layer of the atmosphere?",
      option1: "Mesosphere",
      option2: "Troposphere",
      option3: "Exosphere",
      option4: "Stratosphere",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "A millimetre of mercury is a manometric unit of pressure, defined as precisely 133.322387415 pascals. What is the symbol for a millimetre of mercury?",
      option1: "hhMg",
      option2: "MPA",
      option3: "mmHg",
      option4: "inHg",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Name the atmospheric layer that is completely cloudless and free of water vapor.",
      option1: "Exosphere",
      option2: "Troposphere",
      option3: "Thermosphere",
      option4: "Stratosphere",
      ans: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "The ozone layer or ozone shield is a region of Earth’s atmosphere that absorbs most of the Sun’s ultraviolet (UV) radiation. Which layer of the atmosphere contains ozone layer?",
      option1: "Troposphere",
      option2: "Mesosphere",
      option3: "Thermosphere",
      option4: "Stratosphere",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the average atmospheric pressure at sea level as defined by the International Standard Atmosphere?",
      option1: "101325 pascals",
      option2: "14.6959 pascals",
      option3: "1013 pascals",
      option4: "984.43 pascals",
      ans: 1,
    },
  ];